Jeffrey Lu

Full-Stack Developer

Brooklyn, NY
lu.jeffrey91@gmail.com
(718) 415-8521
LinkedIn
Github | Portfolio

Developer with a background in shipping and logistics. I bring my experience of notable attention to detail, partaking in handling moving parts through production. I relish in the satisfaction of a completed project and patience that comes with it. Combining these experiences, I hope to create more ease of access applications for people across the globe.

SKILLS

- Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, SQL, Mongo, JSON
- Databases: PostgresSQL, MongoDB
- Libraries/Frameworks: React, Express.js, Jquery, Django, version control GIT
- Soft Skills: Customer Service, Customer relations support, Negotiations, Multilingual

PROJECTS

Taco Jump: https://jiffylube.github.io/Taco-Jump/

- Front end game based off of google chrome's dinosaur game
- Built using Javascript, CSS, HTML

Monster Hunter World Project : https://friendly-pie-4f7f43.netlify.app/

- App that allows users to fetch and present data from a database
- Leveraged embedded React, Javascript, Javascript, CSS3, HTML5, to display the visual aspects **mySelfie**: https://thunderous-cendol-805368.netlify.app/
 - Application that allows users to take selfies
 - Front-end built using React.js, react routers
 - Utilized a MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React.js, Node.js) with full with full create, read, update, delete (CRUD) capabilities
 - Utilized Git control during the production of the application with frequent commits until deployment.

EXPERIENCE

General Assembly, New York, NY

Software Engineering Fellow, March 2022 - May 2022

- Designed user facing projects utilizing Javascript and React.js
- Set up back-end website applications, and setup databases using MongoDB, SQL, with other frameworks.
- Collaborated with small teams for building acceptable products within allotted deadlines.

Apex Logistics International, Springfield, NY

Ocean Imports Team Lead, July 2018 - July 2021

Ocean Imports Coordinator, August 2016 - June 2018

- Managed large scale projects for distribution center requirements, and ensured consistent routing options are readily available.
- Handled numerous Dangerous Goods shipments, DG certified.

EDUCATION

General Assembly, *Software Engineering Immersive* | New York, NY | March 2022 - May 2022 **New York City College of Technology,** *Electrical Engineering* | New York, NY | August 2009 - June 2011 **Brooklyn Technical High School,** *Majored in Architecture* | New York, NY | August 2005 - June 2009